Guide to the Shirley Hayes Papers 1948-2001 (Bulk 1952-1979) MS 292
New-York Historical Society
- Series XI. Articles and Clippings, 1952-1980
  - Village newspaper clippings, 1961-1965 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Waterfront issues: Clippings, 1966-1980, Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Lindsay victory—Newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lindsay victory—Newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Efforts to keep folksingers in the Park and prohibit sightseeing buses from parking around the Park, Undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings—Fragments, 1952-1963, Undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Series XII. Visual Materials, 1952-1993
  This series contains visual materials related to Washington Square Park and the traffic plans. The types of materials included are photos, maps, art prints, posters and a banner. Some of these materials are oversized and are located in three oversized boxes (Box 18, 19, and 20), separate from Box 16.
  - Washington Square Park—Contact sheets, Undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Washington Square—Historic photos, Undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - "Washington Square" by Carl Mueller (print), Undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Washington Square Park plans, 1952, Undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - "The Villager Historic Series No. 1"—Grove Court (print), [1993?] (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Site Plan—Title 1—Washington Square South East—Plans, Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Parks Department Washington Square Park plan, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Washington Square Park plan—Prints, 1954, Undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Washington Square Park Arch mockup photo, Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Washington Square Park plan photostats and "Save Washington Square Park" poster, Undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "Save Washington Square Park" banner—Meeting of Board of Estimate, [1958] Sept. 18 (Box 19, Folder oversize)
  - John Lindsay campaign poster and poster mockup for "Save Washington Square Park", Undated (Box 20, Folder oversize)
- Series XIII. Recordings, Undated
  This series contains one reel of recordings about "Saving Washington Square Park".
  - "Saving Washington Square Park", Undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Series XIV. Notes, Drafts, and Fragments, 1953-1967
  This series includes drafts of letters and speeches written about the activities Hayes was involved in.
  - Various other notes, drafts, and fragments, Undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Alienated envelopes, 1953-1967, Undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Series XV. Duplicate and unsorted material, circa 1952-1961
  - Duplicate and unsorted material (box 1 of 4) (Offsite-box 21)
  - Duplicate and unsorted material (box 2 of 4) (Offsite-box 22)
  - Duplicate and unsorted material (box 3 of 4) (Offsite-box 23)
  - Duplicate and unsorted material (box 4 of 4) (Offsite-box 24)
  - Newspapers (box 1 of 3) [RESTRICTED: POOR CONDITION] (Offsite-box 25)
    Restricted
    Material is in very poor condition.
    Scope and Contents
    Park East
    1965: May 6
    Daily Cardinal (University of Wisconsin)
    1962: Jan. 11
    The Democrat (Greenwich Village)
    1961: Sep. 7
    Greenwich Village News
    1960: Nov. 23; Dec. 8
    1961: Jan. 19, 26; Mar. 2
    New York Times
    miscellaneous clippings, 1964–1965
    Caricature: Greenwich Village's Feature Newspaper
    1952: Jan.-June, Nov.-Dec.
    1953: Feb., Apr., May, June
    + miscellaneous clippings
    The Villager
    1952: Nov. 20
    1961: Jan. 26; Feb. 2, 16; Mar. 2, 9, 30; Apr. 20, 27; May 11, 18, 25; June 1, 8, 15; July 27; Aug. 17, 31; Sep. 14, 21; Oct. 5, 12, 19, 26; Nov. 2, 9; Dec. 28
    1962: Jan. 4, 25; Feb. 1, 8
    Village Voice
    1959: Apr. 15; Aug. 26
    1960: Nov. 10
    1961: Feb. 16, 23; Mar. 9, 16, 23; Apr. 13, 27; May 4, 11, 18, 25; June 1, 8, 15, 29; July 6, 20, 27; Aug. 17; Oct. 26; Nov. 2, 16, 30; Dec. 7, 21
  - Newspapers (box 2 of 3) [RESTRICTED: POOR CONDITION] (Offsite-box 26)
    1955: Oct. 26; Nov. 2, 9, 16, 23, 30; Dec. 7, 14, 21, 28
    1956: Jan. 4, 11, 18, 25; Feb. 1, 8, 15, 22, 29; Mar. 14, 21, 28; Apr. 11, 18, 25; May 2, 9, 16, 23, 30; June 13, 27; July; Midsummer; Aug. 29; Sep. 5, 19; Oct. 3, 10, 17, 24, 31; Nov. 7, 14, 21, 28; Dec. 5, 12, 19, 26
    1957: Jan. 9, 23, 30; Feb. 13, 20, 27; Mar. 6, 13, 20, 27; Apr. 3, 10, 17, 24; May 1, 8, 15, 22, 29; June 5, 12, 19, 26; July 10, 17, 24, 31; Aug. 14, 21, 28; Sep. 11, 18, 25; Oct. 2, 16, 23, 30; Nov. 13; Dec. 4, 11, 18, 25
    1958: Jan. 1, 8, 15, 22; Feb. 5, 12; Mar. 12, 19, 26; Apr. 2, 16, 23, 30; May 7, 14, 21, 28; June 4, 18, 25; July 2, 9, 23, 30; Aug. 13, 20, 27; Sep. 3, 10, 17; Oct. 1, 8, 15, 22, 29; Nov. 5, 12, 19, 26; Dec. 3, 10, 17, 24
    1959: Jan. 14, 21, 28; Feb. 4, 18, 25; Mar. 4, 11, 18, 25; Apr. 8, 22; May 13, 20, 27; June 3, 10, 17, 24; July 8, 15, 22, 29; Aug. 5, 12, 19; Sep. 2, 9; Oct. 7, 14, 21, 28; Nov. 4, 11, 18, 25; Dec. 2, 9, 16, 23, 30
    1960: Jan. 6, 13, 20, 27; Feb. 3, 10, 17; Mar. 2, 9, 16, 23, 30; Apr. 6, 13, 20, 27; May 4, 11, 25; June 1, 8, 16, 23, 30; July 7, 21; Aug. 11, 25
    +Duplicates, 1955–1960
    +Miscellaneous clippings
  - Newspapers (box 3 of 3) [RESTRICTED: POOR CONDITION] (Offsite-box 27)
    1952: Mar. 6, 20; Apr. 24; July 3; Sep. 4; Oct. 23, 30
    1953: Jan. 8; Apr. 9, 30; May 7, 14, 21, 28; June 4, 18; Sep. 3, 17, 24; Oct. 29; Nov. 5, 12, 19, 25; Dec. 3, 17, 24
    1954: Jan. 14, 28; Feb. 4, 11, 18, 25; Mar. 4, 11, 18, 25; Mar. 4, 11, 25; Apr. 1, 8, 15, 22, 29; May 6, 13, 27; June 3, 10, 17, 24; July 1, 8, 15, 22, 29; Aug. 5, 12, 19; Sep. 9, 16, 23, 30; Oct. 7, 28; Nov. 4, 11, 18, 24; Dec. 9, 16, 30
    1955: Jan. 6, 20, 27; Feb. 3, 10, 17, 24; Mar. 3, 17, 24, 31; Apr. 7, 14, 21, 28; May 5, 12, 19, 26; June 2, 9, 16, 30; July 7, 21, 28; Aug. 4, 11, 18, 25; Sep. 1, 8, 15, 22; Oct. 6, 13, 20, 27; Nov. 3, 10, 17, 23; Dec. 1, 15
    1957: Feb. 7; Apr. 18, 25; May 2, 9, 16, 23, 29; June 6, 13, 27; July 3, 11, 18, 25; Aug. 8, 15, 22, 29; Sep. 5, 12, 19, 26; Oct. 3
    +Duplicates